#### PERSONAL INFORMATION



## Gourab Paul

- Whitefield, Bangalore, 560037, India
- (+91) 903-583-8711
- gourab.p17@gmail.com
- https://gourab.oyekool.com
- Skype: gourab.p17 | LinkedIn: http://in.linkedin.com/in/gourabpaul

Gender Male | Date of birth 17/10/1989 | Nationality Indian

PREFERRED JOB

After having 6.5 years' of experience with many role and responsibility in software industry, I am looking for new opportunity, either as a full-stack developer, cloud computing, java developer, micro services, machine learning or similar position. I have experience working as a lead developer in start-ups as well as an individual contributor in multinational company with various clients/teams across various countries.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Sep, 2019 - Present

## Cloud Security Engineer Cisco- https://www.cisco.com/

- Integrate CASB and DLP system and monitor events depending on velocity and activities, raise incidents for any abnormal activities on google drive, office 365, ookta, webex, slack and various other vendors.
- Technology/Tools AWS, Jenkins, GIT, Python, apis

## July, 2017 - Sep, 2019

## Module Lead System (Lead developer)

Mphasis- https://www.mphasis.com/. Client: HP Inc - https://hp.com

- Enablement service: Design and develop micro service application in AWS lambda to fetch printer details from PAAS and K2 system and make a single point of contact for both fulfilment need(service delivery) and doppler service.
- JamPublisher: Migrate existing MSSQL database to PostgreSQL and change the respective ORM and java-hibernate. And deploy the same in AWS RDS instance and ECS container
- Billing service: Wireframe and develop billing UI for Staples, JP Morgan and Kaiser client using Angular5 and Typescript and generate ms excel and pdf using handlebars
- Technology/Tools Angular 5, Angular material, angular-cli, Node js, JsReport, Git, Visual Studio Code, NodeJs, Serverless(sls), DynamoDb, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Amazon Web Services, Lambda, api gateway, Git, Npm, Visual Studio Code, Java, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, api gateway, Kibana, Tomcat, Jenkins, Docker, Pipeline, ECS, Liquibase, Maven, Spring
- Team size: 5Process : Agile(Scrum), TFS

# Jan, 2017 – July, 2017 Senior System Engineer (Lead Cloud Engineer) IBM- https://www.ibm.com/. Client: DTCC - http://www.dtcc.com/ Migrate existing monolithic service oriented architecture(SOA) Credit derivatives warehouse to microservices and serverless api using Node Js and Angular 2/4 Technology/Tools - NodeJs, PassportJs, Restify, Mongoose, MongoDB, sequelize, postgresgl, Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, Amazon Web Services, Lambda, Spring-boot, api, Bitbucket, Angular2/4, Typescript, SPA(Single Page application), Gulp, Visual Studio Code ○ Team size: 8 ○ Process : Agile(Scrum), Jira May, 2016 – Jan, 2017 Senior Software Engineer (Lead developer) Niranta Solutions & Services Pvt Ltd - http://www.niranta.in/. Project: Talhunt Develop products using Spring MVC and Node.js on the back end, Angular JS (SPA) at the front end, and Google Cloud(Firebase) for authentication for ATS(automatic tracking system) and HRM(human resource management) Technology/Tools - Node js, AWS(EC2, EBS, Route 53, Cloud front, SES, SQS, SNS, RDS), Google cloud(Bucket, Firebase), Spring JDBC, Spring mvc, rest apis, Java Mailer, Velocity Template, MySql, Junit, Maven, Intellij IDE, Apache tomcat 7, BitBucket, Angular Js, Bootstrap 3, HTML5, Yeoman, Bower, Grunt, Visual Studio Code IDE ○ Team size: 8 O Process: Agile(Scrum, Kanban), TFS Nov, 2015 – May, 2016 Java Developer (Software Consultant) Quantiphi - <a href="https://www.quantiphi.com/">https://www.quantiphi.com/</a>. Client: HeavyWater - <a href="https://www.heavywater.com/">https://www.quantiphi.com/</a>. Design and deployed web application and micro services for research analysis of OCR extracted insurance paper using Amazon Web Services for laaS(EC2, load balancers), PaaS(S3) and SaaS(SWF) O Technology/Tools - Amazon Web Services, AWS EC2, AWS Dynamo DB, AWS SWF, Cloud Computing, AWS S3, J2EE, RESTful Web Services (CXF and Jersey), Microservices, Junit, Mockito, Maven, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Eclipse IDE, Agile(Scrum)

## Mar, 2013 – Nov, 2015

## Senior System Engineer (Software developer)

Tata Consultancy Services - https://www.tcs.com/.

O Team size: 10

 OM (Client: Post Finance - Switzerland): Generate ISO standard Delivery Instruction and Output Management using Java.

Process : Agile(Scrum), Jira

- CPM (Client: Target Canada): Improving performance by changing Inline SQL query to Stored Procedure for Change price management application
- Bancs (Client: Santander Bank UK): Developed e-banking transaction (opening fixed deposit, transferring money to different currency account). And updating the same in top tier data base
- Citi Bank (Client: Post Finance Hong Kong and Singapore): Manual Testing of user interface. Has been involved in writing test cases and test scenario.

<ul> <li>Technology/Tools - Java, J2EE, OOPs, S</li> </ul>	Spring-Batch, JSP, Se	rvlet, HTML, CSS,
JavaScript, Oracle WebLogic, Eclipse IDE		

○ Team size: 15 ○ Process : Waterfall

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

## Aug, 2008 – May, 2012 Bachelor of Technology (B-Tech.) in Information Technology

Completed Bachelor degree from West Bengal University of Technology (Siliguri Institute of Technology) with CGPA 7.36 (out of 10)

## July,2006 - June, 2008 Higher Secondary in Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics

Completed Higher secondary (12th) education from Assam Higher Secondary Educational Council (Ramanuj Gupta Junior College) with 66% mark

## Jan, 1996 - May, 2006 Secondary level in Science and English

Completed secondary level (10th) from Secondary Education Board of Assam (Silchar Collegiate School) with 78% mark

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s) Bengali

Other Languages English (Proficient) Hindi (Advanced)

Organisational skills

- Mentorship currently responsible for training and mentoring fresher
- Team player has been awarded with best team player
- Individual contributor currently responsible for requirement gathering of the product, architectural design, development and then deploying the application to production.

#### Technical skills

- Languages: Nodejs, Javascript, Java, AWS cloud
- Cloud-Computing: Amazon Web Services(EC2, Lambda, server less api, Load Balancer, S3, SWF, SES, SQS, SNS), Google cloud (GCE, Firebase, Bucket), scalable Micro Services, Distributed systems
- DBMS: Oracle, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDb, DynamoDB, postgresql
- Web technology: Angular, Typescript, HTML-5, CSS-3, AJAX, Jquery, JSON, XML, JavaScript, Agile, Maven, Bootstrap-3, Junit/Mock Test, SOA, Responsive web design, Git, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Elastic search, Kibana, Web Services, MVC architecture, Spring, Design Pattern, PassportJs, Data structures and algorithms
- Tools: Eclipse, SQL developer, Intellij, MySql workbench, Visual Studio Code, jupyter notebook
- OS- Windows, Linux
- Domain knowledge: Banking, Finance and Retail domain.

#### Other skills

- Blogging https://oyekool.com
- Content Creation https://youtube.com/codespace

## Interests

- Block chain
- Investment banking
- Deep learning

#### Hobbies

- Playing badminton, chess
- Trekking and exploring new places